洁身自好是你的责任
Your cleanliness is your responsibility,
但我希望你不要掉以轻心  我建议你着佩
but I expect it taken serious. I shall advise on
腰带 胸花 袜带及裙撑
girdle, corsage, garter and bustle,
若想发达 请务必听从我的建议 如今这里能
advice by which you will abide if you wish to thrive. Now the house
为我们带来60%的收入
takes 60% of all earnings.
这差不多算是最好的路子了 姑娘
It is a good sight less than most, girl.
当然 你所得到的回报将是
In return, you shall find
无忧无虑 不再有任何烦恼
yourself free from harassment of any kind.
倘若你事后要提出起诉 我也会站在你这边的
If you have a complaint to make, I will take your side,
无论对方有什么背景 或是他人有什么质疑
no matter the grounds nor the Thomas in question.
简而言之 你将丰衣足食
In short, you will find yourself fed,
平安无事 无债一身轻
safe and solvent.
好好考虑一下  想好了给我答复
Think on it. Return once you have.
好的 夫人
Yes, ma'am.
Lucy
Lucy!
Oh, Lucy!
哦 亲爱的
Oh, darling.
我会清扫并擦洗地板
I'll sweep and scrub the floors,
为店里的姑娘们换洗床单被单
change the girls' linen,
为她们做饭 一切听您指示
cook for them, do whatever you ask of me.
Lucy 让你做女佣? 姑娘们把你当成好姐姐
Ah, Lucy. You, a char? You would make step-sisters of my girls
如果让你当女佣 不到一周她们就会闹事的
and I would have mutiny in a week.
快告诉我  这几年你都去哪儿了
Now, tell me. Where have you been these last years?
有没有哪位绅士娶你回家呢
Did one of our gentlemen make you his own?
- Lucy?   - 求您了 Susan小姐
- Lucy? - Please, Miss Susan.
您不让我在这里做工吗
Will you not let me work?
你知道的 我不可以
You know I cannot.
那我就不知道自己会变成怎样了
Then I know not what will become of me.
Lucy 看看你
Lucy, look at you.
这个世界的真理便是 男人们为图享乐
The truth of this world is that men have designed it
按照自己的欲求改变它
for their own purpose and pleasure.
而你 亲爱的 你满足了他们那幼稚思想中
And you, my darling, there is not one primitive desire
一切原始的欲望
in their child-like minds that you do not fulfil.
夫人 这也是我的不幸
Which is my curse, miss...
它让世界上所有人得益
one from which all the world profit...
除了我
save myself...
而且如今看来 我无法逃避这不幸
and one, it seems, I cannot now escape.
我的天哪
Christ on a pony.
死了 杀人了
Dead. Murdered.
谁 女士?
Who is, lady?
没关系的  没事的
It's all right. It's all right.
===BTM字幕组出品===
本字幕仅供交流 切勿商用
翻译：严冬 绿袖子 蝴蝶 杜杜子 醉醉
开膛街
校对：小已
后期：迷毁
两先令就够了
Two shillings is all.
少买一些黄油 就能多买一些啤酒
You spend less on butter, more perhaps on ale.
为了城市的利益
在你需要的时候让你飘飘欲仙
But a drop or three will raise you up when you need raising
然后将你带入安然与平静
and it's going to bring you peace after.
快  来人 帮帮我
Help! Help me, somebody.
见鬼  快去叫探长
Hell's bells! Fetch the inspector!
女士 来 坐下  你刚才遭遇了什么
Come sit down here, Miss. What you been up to?
- Lucy吗   - 这什么情况  她是谁
- Lucy? - What is this? Who is she?
她叫Lucy  Lucy Eames
Her name's Lucy. Lucy Eames.
你们怎么认识的
Known to you how?
你觉得呢  她曾是Susan那儿的姑娘
How do you think? She was one of Susan's.
Lucy   - 身上的血不是她的 谢天谢地
Lucy. - Blood's not hers, thank God.
那是谁的
Then whose?
长官 她刚才提到了谋杀
Sir, she spoke of murder.
- 两场谋杀   - 姑娘 在哪里
- Two murders. - Where, girl?
狗脖儿胡同
Dog's Neck.
强布尔街后面的贫民?他们这么叫那个地儿
It's what they call the rookery off the back of Cable.
- 圣乔治十字旗附近?   - 没错
- St George's Cross? - That's right, sir.
今天应该是有拆迁队到那个贫民窟去
That slum's due to meet the wrecking crew today.
能给我一个毯子吗  请给我一个毯子
Can we get a blanket? Give me a blanket.
女士 跟我来  来
Miss, come here. Come here.
女士 看到那个大胡子先生了吗
Miss, you see this whiskered gentleman here?
你可以叫他Artherton先生
His name is Mr Artherton.
有任何需要 尽管找他
You have need of anything, you ask him.
她或许有罪  或许蒙冤
She may deserve them. She may not.
- 还是小心行事为好   - 没错
- Best not take chances. - Quite so.
警长 这位女士似乎对监禁不陌生
Sergeant, that girl's no stranger to restraints.
派人去发电报吧
Get the telegraph singing.
查查看我们兄弟警区
See if any of our brethren had any cause
问他们是否曾因某种原因关押过Lucy Eames
to lock up a Lucy Eames.
- 可能是因为卖淫罪   - 是 长官
- Tart, I believe. - Yes, sir.
你说她是Hart女士店里的姑娘?
She's one of Miss Hart's girls, you say?
曾经是   - 什么时候
Was. - When?
大概两年前吧
Two years ago maybe.
Susan在莱姆豪斯运河
Susan found her lifting her
莱姆豪斯运河: 伦敦东部的一条运河
莱姆豪斯:伦敦东部区名 以贫穷肮脏而著名
发现她在为一个搬运工掀起自己的衬裤
drawers for the hauliers on Limehouse Cut,
就把她收留下来 养到16岁 然后放她离开了
took her in, fed her, waited till she was 16, let her loose.
她很厉害的 Reid
She was something, Reid.
想要她的男人们都能排到霍斯顿的半路了
Men stood in line half-way to Hoxton.
她真幸运
Lucky girl.
可是为什么他们突然不要她了呢
So why did they stop queuing?
把这些人赶出去  快  走起来
Get these people out of here. Come on. Move along.
不管你走不走 今天都要清拆房屋
It's all coming down today whether you're out or not.
南方&中心铁路
白教堂
隧道点
南方&中心铁路指令征用
警察来了  请让一让 各位
Police coming through. Stand aside, gentlemen.
抱歉 夫人  请让开
Excuse me, madam. Stand aside.
出去  都出去
Move! Out!
你 出去
You, out!
已经死了  断气没多久
He's gone. Though not long since.
身体还没冷下来
Still warm.
你就站在那眼睁睁地看着他失血而亡?
You. You stand there and watch this man bleed out?
这家伙  没错
That man... I did.
- 他是谁   - 他叫Roach
- Who is he? - Name's Roach.
在这一带收租金的
Collected rents hereabout.
今天这房子就要拆了 他还来这干嘛
What use was he on the day this building comes down?
不知道为什么 他们开始大吵大闹
Whatever it was, they raised hell about it.
她说他是恶魔 他发誓如果她再不闭嘴
She calling him a devil, he swearing to end her
- 就弄死她   - 这个女人?
- if she didn't pipe herself down. - The woman?
没错 Maggie Eames  这是她的房子
Yeah, Maggie Eames. This is her place.
那些在外面哭的是她的孩子?
And those her children that wail out there?
是她的孩子和他们的婊子姐姐
Them and their whore of a sister.
警长 把他们带出去
Sergeant, get them out of here. Have a
派一个人带他们到莱萌街
man take them to their sister
去找他们的姐姐   - 是 长官
at Leman Street. - Yes, sir.
那个妓女在你们那?
You have the tart?
- 你看到她了?   - 我看到她
- You saw her? - She was seen...
从这里走出去 被他的血淋了一身
walking out of here like she'd washed herself in his blood.
你有注意到其他人吗
You take note of any other?
在这样的日子?  在大家都急忙搬离的日子?
On this day?! Amongst this exodus?
就算是撒旦亲临
Satan himself could have
在此逍遥漫步 也不会有人有闲心议论
sauntered through and no man remark on it.
- 你叫?   - Denton
- Your name? - Denton.
到外面等着  警长 关上门
Wait outside. Sergeant, shut the door.
- Constable 看住这个人   - 是 长官
- Constable, keep hold of this man. - Yes, sir.
看来 她将玻璃瓶砸向他的头
So, she smashes the bottle into his head.
又用碎渣刺他的喉咙
She stabs his throat with it.
他腿脚不稳 举枪发射
He staggers, he shoots...
- 非也   - 怎样?
- No. - What?
这个伤口 看这里的皮肤 皮下脂肪
This wound, the skin, subcutaneous fat...
刺口整齐利索  如果她是用玻璃瓶刺他
See how clean it's penetrated? She stabbed him with that bottle,
伤口应参差不齐
the work would be jagged
血肉应碎烂模糊  而这是个整齐的切口
and the flesh scragged. This is a lancing.
一刀刺入 准确无误
Just one precise thrust.
是Eames小姐杀的
Miss Eames, then.
我们见到她的时候她没有带刀
She had no blade on her when she arrived.
- 可能是她把刀丢掉了   - 没错
- She could've ditched it. - Certainly.
不过
But...
从她所站位置走到他身边还需破费周折
But she would have struggled to reach him from where she stood.
Lucy站在...
Lucy stood...
这里
here.
看到他动脉血的喷射弧度了吗
See the arc of arterial blood?
心脏跳动压迫血液从割开的动脉喷出
The heart's beat projects it from his severed artery,
喷到这面墙 这面墙 这扇窗户
strikes this wall, this wall, this window...
喷到那位女生身上 因此那面墙上少了一块印迹
Then hits the girl, leaving that gap.
答对了 加十分
Give the man a cigar.
他被另一个人从后面刺了一刀
He was cut from behind by someone else.
继续说   - 她用酒瓶袭击他
Go on. - She hits him with the gin bottle,
他"砰"地一声开枪
blam, he shoots.
被人从背后一刺  他转过身来
Gets stabbed from behind. He turns.
他倒下之时动脉里的血喷射到墙上
He falls with the stripe of blood.
以及Lucy身上
Towards Lucy.
此时他又开一枪 没中  看到了吗
But he shoots and misses. See that?
没打中是因为他在转身 瞄准另一个人  砰
Missing because he's turning, aiming for another. Blam.
砰
Blam.
砰  瞄准的是用刀刺他的人
Blam. Towards whoever cut him.
最后一枪 第六枪在哪里
Where's the last? The sixth?
- 比其他几抢要低 长官   - 确是如此
- Lower than the others, sir. - It is.
没错 不过 会不会是子弹从哪擦过改变了方向
It is, but... was it diverted?
擦到哪里
By what?
上校 看到这个了吗
You see this, Captain?
一共六颗子弹  她头上一颗
We have six bullets. We have one in her head.
四颗直接射向墙壁 顺序合理明了
Four passing directly into the wall in a correlating tangent.
最后一颗 也就是第六颗
And the last, the sixth,
可能转向了 然后穿过这个窗户射了出去
perhaps diverted through this window.
要的就是那颗子弹
Then that's the slug we need.
找到你了
Got ya.
它穿过玻璃之前的确打中过一个人  上面有血
It did pass through a body on its way out. It's blooded.
也就是说
Then...
第四个人站在
a fourth stood...
这里  手握杀死这家伙的匕首
here. In their hand, the knife that killed this man
从他身上 我们可以找到
and with him the answer as to why
他在死前打爆这位女士脑袋的原因
he blew this woman's brains out of her before he died.
标记好这些尸体位置
These bodies, mark where
然后把它们送到你的验尸间
they lay and they are for your dead room.
警长 封锁这间房子  真相就在其间
Sergeant, keep this room sealed. There will be truth in it,
但我们必须一点一点地调查 寻求答案
but we must work it inch by every inch to find it.
你是警察吗
You're police?
我是伦敦郡议会的Stanley Bone
My name is Stanley Bone of the LCC.
我叫Reid  是H警区的
Mine Reid. H Division.
是什么风把我们新郡议会议员
What does it brings a board member
吹到贫民窟清拆这儿来了
of our new county council out to a slum clearance?
您将您的房子提供给这些交房后无处可居之民了吗
Do you offer your home to those here rendered without?
Reid先生 我是制造这场拆迁的
Mr Reid, I am advocate for the railway company
铁路公司的支持者
that makes this incursion.
不管是什么吸引你来此 这事发生在我们的地盘
Whatever has called you here takes place on its land.
我因谋杀案而来
It is murder that calls me here.
谋杀案?  谁被谋杀了
Murder? Of who?
一名收租者和房客
Of a rent collector and tenant.
很遗憾 探长
I am sorry, Inspector.
不过尽管我会为那个死去的可怜人祈祷
But whilst I pray for the poor departed,
这座房子必须今日拆迁
that building comes down today.
不行  在我搞清楚事情始末之前 谁也不准拆
No longer. It stays upright until I know what took place there.
那在你调查租务纠纷之时
And these workmen will stand idle on full wage
我们雇佣的这些全职工人都要一直在此无所事事吗
while you discern the details of a rent dispute?
不论我要调查什么 他们都不准开工
Whatever it is that's discerned here, yes, they will.
或者说您并不支持警察工作?
Or are you not also advocate of the police?
当然支持
Yes, of course.
探长 您可要尽善其责
You must do your duty, Inspector.
现在怎样 探长大人
How now, Inspector?
是来看拆迁的进度的吗
Come to see the march of progress, have we?
看看那些寻求栖身之地的人能否如愿?
Those who now must find their shelter where they can?
那是你关心的事
That your story, is it?
我可是个有同情心之人
Oh, I am a man of compassion.
愚昧之人要么在这样的地方干活谋生
The benighted souls who must make their lives in such places
要么丧命于此
or meet their deaths there.
透露一两个名字就够了 探长大人
Just a name or two, Inspector, eh?
这边总有人会告诉我的
Someone here shall tell me eventually.
为什么你就不能说呢
Why should it not be you?
因为这会给你的生活
Because I would make your life harder
带来不必要的麻烦 Best先生
than it need be, Mr Best.
而不是更加简单
Not the reverse.
不会有事的 Lucy  会好起来的
It'll be all right, Lucy. It'll be all right.
Artherton 派一辆车到圣乔治十字旗附近去
Artherton, a Maria for St George's Cross.
圣乔治十字旗:英格兰国旗
令Jackson上校全速返回
Have Captain Jackson return with all... speed.
好了好了  乖  嘘
There, there. Come on. Shush.
你怎么来了
What's brought you here?
我们的Lucy 探长
Erm, our Lucy, Inspector.
Susan女士让我来看看她
Miss Susan sent me to check on her.
她的情况如何
And how do you find her?
如您所见 Reid先生  她沉默于痛苦之中
As you see her, Mr Reid. Just... silent in her distress.
- 回家吧 姑娘   - 是 长官
- Get home, girl. - Yes, sir.
那位姑娘的到来似乎让她平静了一些 长官
She seemed calmed by the girl's presence, sir.
- 我以为这有益于她   - 没关系的
- I thought it conducive. - Never mind that,
Artherton  你有没有调查一下她
Artherton. Have you traced her?
我没有 长官  这个小伙子调查了
Not myself, sir. The lad.
说吧 Hobbs
Well, Hobbs?
长官 对我来说 那个女孩只是看起来很悲痛
Well, it's only that the girl seems sad, to me, sir.
并不坏   - 不坏
Not bad. - No.
如您所说 她曾戴过镣铐
And like you said, she's worn irons before now,
因此我到各个收容所转了转
so I did a round of the asylums.
有没有查出什么
And you found knowledge of her?
有的 长官  在贝思纳尔格林的云雀宅
Yes, sir. The Lark House at Bethnal Green.
他们有没有派人来
And do they send someone?
来了一位Crabbe医生
A Dr Crabbe comes.
- Karl Crabbe亲自来了?   - 是的长官
- Karl Crabbe himself? - Sir.
他在歇斯底里症研究方面颇有成就
He's made a progress with hysterics
目前这一领域的医生还无人能敌
that no other doctor of the mind has yet.
干得好 Hobbs  你做得对
Good work, Hobbs. You did right.
选两个人 乘警车去找Drake警长吧
Choose two men, take a Maria to Sergeant Drake.
他会指示你该做什么
He'll have instructions for you.
- 遵命 长官   - 把手铐的钥匙给我
- Yes, sir. - Give me the keys to those cuffs.
坐下
Sit.
不  不 孩子  我不是要你来此做这些的
No. No, child. That is not what is... required of you here.
你有没有哪里受伤
Are you wounded in any way?
坐下吧
Sit.
我只希望你开口说话
All I want from you is to talk.
只要您高兴 长官
Whatever pleases you, sir.
喝吧
Drink this.
你还记得是因为什么来到这里吗
Can you remember what it was brought you here?
在狗脖儿胡同发生了什么
What happened at the Dog's Neck?
我的妈妈被杀了 长官
My mama killed, sir.
不仅仅是你的妈妈吧
Not just your mother.
还有一个男人
A man, too.
没错  你认识他吗
Yes. Do you know him?
你看到了什么
What did you see?
恕我冒昧 Eames小姐
Forgive me, Miss Eames.
他的血溅了你一身
His blood was shed all upon you.
长官 我可以离开了吗
May I go now, sir?
Lucy 你以为你现在在哪里
Where is it that you think you are, Lucy?
我忘了
I forget.
你的妈妈 还有这个男人...
Your mama, this man...
帮我 也是帮你自己 好好想想
Help me, help you and think.
你看到了什么
What did you see?
我只看到了我的黑暗
Just my darkness.
当我醒来 他们就躺在我面前
When I woke up, they were there laid before me.
没有其他人?
And not another soul?
没有   - 你确定?
No-one. - You are sure?
长官 这世上没有我确定之事
There's nothing that I'm sure of in this world, sir.
Lucy 你知道你怀孕了吗
Lucy, you are aware that you are with child, are you not?
Crabbe医生
Dr Crabbe.
Lucy
Lucy!
Reid先生
Mr Reid.
医生
Sir.
我上个月听了您的演讲  在林肯律师学院
I heard you speak last month. At Lincoln's Inn.
在学院的那次  我认识的一个人跟我说
At the college! A man I know told me
那天我语调低沉 内容单调
I droned that day.
那他一定没有认真听
He cannot have been listening.
现在你找到了我们的Lucy 并照顾她
And now you have found and cared for our Lucy.
Crabbe医生 我想告诉您
Dr Crabbe, you should know,
Eames小姐的妈妈今天被杀害了
Miss Eames' mother is killed this day.
哦 我可怜的孩子
Oh, my poor dear girl.
被杀害的还有另一个人
And another man, too,
名为Roach  您认识他吗?
the name of Roach. Do you know him, sir?
不 我不认识  Lucy怀孕了?
No, I do not. Was Lucy present?
是的
She was.
但是什么都不记得了?
But remembers not a thing?
把这些尸体送到我的验尸房去
Get both these bodies to my dead room!
谁出了差错就去协助我验尸
The man who drops them will be assisting me at autopsy.
不要  等等  等等
No! Wait! Wait!
快抬走  快  迅速点
Take them away now! Hurry! Hurry!
Reid 很 很抱歉
Reid, I... I'm sorry.
她患有癫痫?
She is epileptic?
她受癫痫折磨 没错  还有其他病症
She is ailed by that, yes. Other conditions, also.
探长 我知道你还想继续审问她
Inspector, I know you must question her further
但你再次需要她之前 我要先带回去照顾她
but I would lodge her in my care until you next have need of her.
Artherton 准备文件
Artherton, prepare the papers.
Davis 帮我抱起她
Davis, can we lift her?
谢谢
Thank you.
好了 Lucy  没事了 没事了
There Lucy. All is well, all is well.
Crabbe医生 在您离开之前我想再问一句
Dr Crabbe, one last question before you go.
Eames小姐做您的病人已经多久了?
For how long has Miss Eames been a patient of yours?
两年多一点
A little over two years now,
不过她不是一直跟我住在一起
but she is not permanently resident with me.
您没有一直照管着她吗
You keep no watch over her?
探长 要想治好她的病
Inspector, to find her health,
让她感觉自己像你我一样
it is of considerable importance
正常地生活无比重要
that Lucy's life feel as commonplace as yours or mine.
如果让她觉得我们在评判她的一举一动
That cannot be the case
那恢复健康便是无望
if she feel we assess her every move.
她不舒服的时候 就去找我
When she is ill, she comes to me.
没事的时候 就爱怎么生活就怎么生活
When well, she lives as she pleases.
不好意思
Excuse me.
长官  这些小家伙们
Sir. These nippers?
我知道一个地方可以收养他们
I have an idea where they may rest
在他们得到更好的归宿之前
until we know better what will become of them.
Goren小姐  Goren小姐 很抱歉
Miss Goren? Miss Goren, I am sorry.
我又来麻烦您了
I come to impose on you once more.
哦  朋友之间不必见外 探长
Oh! We are friends now, Inspector.
想来就来 完全不必道歉
You must never apologise for your visit.
这位小姑娘是Betsy
This is Betsy.
你好啊 Betsy
Hello, Betsy!
孩子们 快来欢迎小妹妹Betsy
Girls, say hello to Betsy.
这个可怜的孩子经历了怎样的故事
What is this poor child's story?
她的妈妈死了 她姐姐...
Er, her mother is dead and her sister...
她姐姐暂时照顾不了她
Her sister is of no use to her for now.
没有爸爸或叔叔什么的吗
No father or uncle?
这个家庭就是被男人毁掉的 Goren小姐
It's men that are the ruin of this family, Miss Goren.
不仅仅是这个家庭 好多都是如此 探长
Oh, this family and many like them, Inspector.
你不这么认为吗
You disagree?
哦 不 不是的 只是 我妻子也会这样说
No, no. No, merely, my wife would say the same.
Reid夫人一定是一位理智聪慧
Mrs Reid must be a woman
心智明晰的女人
of great sense and clarity.
没错 她是
She is that, yes.
那我希望与她一见
Then I would like to meet her.
再次多谢 Goren小姐
My many thanks again, Miss Goren.
如果有什么消息 我会首先通知你
If I have news, you'll be the first to know.
你还记得你的屋子吗 Lucy
You remember, Lucy? Your room?
一切都没变
Just as it ever was.
奇怪 就好像她从不曾在这里过
Strange, were like she weren't even there.
几乎都认不出我来
Barely even recognised me.'
总之 我不理解你为什么
Anyways, I don't know why you're
要对她如此不遗余力的讨好
getting yourself in such a palaver about her.
你是不是认为她像Ellen Terry一样
Think she gave two tosses for
Ellen Terry 著名的莎士比亚话剧演员
四处漂泊后就能身价倍增?
you when she swanned off like Ellen Terry herself?
丫头 她可比你金贵多了
She was worth ten of you, girl.
哦 Rose 过来过来  我真的很抱歉
Oh, Rose, come here, come here. I'm so sorry.
我为她担心  而且我感到自责
I fear for her. And I blame myself.
警长 把Reid找来
Get Reid, Sergeant.
是 Munro警监
Yes, Commissioner Munro.
我要说两件事 Reid
Two issues, Reid.
第一 不管这是谁做的 这个人是从背后下的手
One, whoever did this. From behind.
他是从低处向上发力
They had to push upwards from underneath to do so.
所以我推测他的身高较矮
So I reckon they would be shorter.
刀的长度大约十厘米
The blade's about four inches.
很锋利 应该是折叠刀  而且制作精良
A good point, a switch-blade most likely. A well-made one.
那么第二点呢
The second issue?
这个女人
This woman.
子宫里长了子宫肌瘤
There are fibroids in her womb.
解释一下
Explain.
类似溃疡 时间久了子宫就会畸形
It's like cankers. Over time they deform the uterus.
会影响生育吗
The children?
她已经十年未曾生育了
She ain't been confined for over ten years.
那是为什么 莫非那些孩子是Lucy的
So what then? Are they Lucy's?
长官 警监Munro让您过去
Commissioner Munro calls for you, Sir.
他要你陪他去一趟狗脖儿胡同的铁路挖掘现场
You're to go with him to the Dog's Neck railway excavation.
那里才开发了几周
They are but a few weeks old,
但已经带来了亘古不散的寒意
but these places already have the chill of eternity.
长官 你为什么叫我来
Why bring me here, Sir?
Reid 只想让你亲自听听这个人的话
Just hear the man out, Reid.
他的意见是我们不该忽视的
His concern should be ours, also.
探长 探长 请这边来
Inspector. Inspector, please!
谢谢你迅速赶到
Thank you for responding so speedily to my invitation.
我很欣慰 特别是对你 探长
Yourself in particular, Inspector.
有话直说 Bone 我那里还有两个谋杀案等着呢
Get to it, Bone, I have two murders above us need investigation.
我一定会速战速决 不多叨扰 Reid先生
And I will have you returned to them in short order, Mr Reid.
等你看过这里到底在修建什么之后
As soon as you've seen just what is built here.
铺设铁路而已 多新鲜啊
Track is laid. For a railway. It is nothing new.
或许不新鲜  但绝对有新意
Perhaps not new. But newly efficient.
所有人 离开铁路一米
Every man - a yard back from the line!
有500伏特的电压运行在
500 volts run beneath the
利物浦大街的枢纽站的河水下
rivers of the junction at Liverpool Street,
从那里分支 分别向东 西方 延伸
split there to travel east, west and onwards, Mr Reid.
Reid先生 不停地延伸着 不停地
Onwards, for ever.
延伸过下一个世纪 再下一个
Down the next century and the one that follows -
组成一张有机的运输网
an organism of transport.
每一个区都彼此相连
Every borough connected, one to the other.
旅行不再仅仅是富人的特权
The poor, sir - not simply the rich - will travel,
因为旅费会大幅下降
for the cost of half a pot of jam,
从城市的一边到另一边花费无几
from one end of our city to another.
随着每天他们的视野的开拓
Their everyday horizon extended,
他们的志向也会相应提高
their aspirations improved accordingly.
Bone先生 我从未质疑过
Mr Bone, I have never contested
这项工程对人们的生活的意义
the value of this machinery to people's lives.
那就促进它吧
Then assist it.
探长 我们为这个事业所投入的资金网
Inspector, the investment structure we have constructed for this
犹如我们即将建造的铁路网
venture, it is as reticulated
都层层相套 环环相扣
as the network we would build.
每一个环节都有一个完工保障
Each section of line has a completion guarantee.
只有保证这个环节完成
That guarantee fulfilled,
下一部分的建筑资金才会发放
the next tranche of capital is released.
如果地面上的拆迁人员继续无所事事
Should the demolition crew above ground stand idle
我们这里整个工程就会有毁于一旦的危险
for many hours more, we risk the collapse of the entire venture.
所以我拜托你 先生 求求你了
I beg you, sir. I beg you.
让他们继续开工吧
Let them proceed.
日安 先生们
Good day to you, fine sirs.
这位是谁啊
Who is this gentleman?
他叫Best 他是星报的撰稿记者
His name is Best. He writes for The Star.
议员先生 您并不认得我 但我今天是来结交您的
You know me not, Councillor. But I come to know you, Sir.
这里是私人产业
This is private land.
马上滚蛋 否则Reid探长会用靴底送你一程
Remove yourself or Inspector Reid shall do so with his boot.
可此刻我站在一块公共区域上
And this here is common land
在此我想提问Bone先生几个问题
from which I shall ask Mr Bone my questions,
就是他是如何评价 在他投身郡议会的
of how he feels, four months into its life,
四个月里 议会的作为呢
our new county council proceeds.
如果议会启蒙公民的职能 还没有被议员们
If its civic enlightenments are not compromised by the...
追逐铜臭的商业心所瓦解的话
commercial instincts of its councillors.
我不想在这接着听你含沙射影了
I shall not stand here and listen to these insinuations.
我们所做的一切都是为了整个城市
Everything we do, we do for the good of this city
为了城市里百姓大众们的利益
and the benefit of those who build their lives within it.
警监 探员 我先失陪了
Commissioner, Inspector.
先生 我很确定人们会感谢你的付出
I'm sure they appreciate your dedication, sir.
尤其是您对您自家幸福的牺牲
Yes, the sacrifices you have made to your own life.
您的妻子 眼睁睁看着海水长驱直入进了霍夫镇
Your wife, watching the sea roll in all alone down in Hove.
您膝下无子
No children to comfort you.
不能享受天伦之乐
The pleasures of a home
却为了他人的幸福而活
life foregone in pursuit of others' happiness.
先生 这一定令您伤怀
It must ail you, Sir.
即便您性格强韧 也必定黯然神伤吧
It must play on those finely-tuned nerves of yours.
还是说您已经在其他方面找到慰藉了呢
Or do you find other ways of easing that pain...?
Best 你说够了没  快滚
Best! Enough. Get gone.
悉听尊便 探长
Whatever you say, Inspector.
但我还会回来的
But do not think me gone long.
就我个人来说 Bone先生对未来的规划
For myself, Mr Bone's vision
就是交通密集型城市的构想 我不置可否
of a liberal city commune is of little bearing.
是的 长官
No, sir.
对我而言重要的是
What is of greater importance to me is this
一旦一个既成的平民窟
that each occasion a slum is raised to the ground,
被整洁的钢筋水泥所取代
it is replaced by the type of brick and clean steel on which
那么滋生罪恶的温床也就不存在了
the bacteria of the criminal classes can no longer fester.
要是我们能把大量游民送到外面的广阔世界
The greater the number of homeless we send to the wider world,
我们的犯罪率就会显著下降
the faster our measure of crime falls.
我就是这个意思 探长
You have my meaning, inspector.
不管你的人在贫民窟里有什么要事
Whatever it is your men do in that rookery,
都要在天黑之前干完
it stops by end of day
否则 他们就会发现自己置身在碎石瓦砾中了
or they will find themselves amidst the rubble.
总会留下蛛丝马迹的
'There will be sign.'
也许这人行踪鬼魅 如同幽灵
This person might have vanished as if a ghost,
但他终究不是幽灵
but a ghost they are not.
他所经过的地方
Wherever they have passed, the space
必定会印刻下他的所作所为
through which they have done so must bear witness.
咱们三个 咱们还得一起再检查一次这个地方
We three - we take one more pass of this place together.
快点跪下来查啊
On your knees, then.
Hobbs 发现什么了
What, Hobbs? What is it?
是杜松子酒 先生
It's gin, Sir.
长官  快看这个 金色的头发
Sir? Look at this, blonde hair.
极有可能是那个母亲的
The mother's, most likely.
那是什么
What's that?
是香草
It's a herb.
掉下来的 被碾压过
Dropped. Brushed aside.
是我以前闻过的味道
One that I have smelled before.
Hobbs  是时候去多了解一下
Hobbs. It's time we knew more
死去的Roach先生了
about our dead Mr Roach.
去公司登记局  弄清楚有关于他的工作的情况
Get to Companies House. Find out what you can about his work,
看看他到底是给自己收租金
whether he collected on his own behalf
还是帮其他人收   - 是 长官
or for others. - Sir.
警长 你跟我走
Sergeant - you're with me.
对于这里到底发生了什么 我已经有头绪了
I have a notion of what may have passed here.
到楼上去才能进一步 流氓
That's for upstairs, cheeky.
Drake警长
Sergeant Drake!
你这个瘦皮猴 快滚出去吧
Get your skinny prick out of here!
快叫Susan女士来
Fetch Miss Susan!
你要逮捕我吗 先生
Will you arrest me, Sir?
不会的 姑娘
No, girl.
我只是希望他不会白吃你的豆腐
I hope he's not left you out of pocket.
Drake先生 你真是太风趣了
Mr Drake, you do say the funniest things.
你的女主人呢 她在哪儿
Your mistress. Where is she?
最好告诉我你们是来突袭的
This had best be a raid.
如果你们大张旗鼓地过来只是为了说个晚安
If you've come simply to say your good-evenings,
我可就要跟你们寻求赔偿了
I shall be seeking compensation.
跟说什么晚安半点儿关系没有
No good-evenings.
我们也不是来突然袭击的
This is not a raid, either.
我只是想来问几个问题 女士
I seek an interview, Madam.
跟我来  不过让你的警长就留在楼下吧
This way. But leave your sergeant down there.
这样他还能免费意淫我的小妞呢
He may moon at my girl gratis.
我在外面等你 长官
I'll be outside sir.
这是你好基友的屋子
Your accomplice's very own suite.
Hart小姐 请问您能谅解我吗
Will you indulge me, Miss Hart?
谅解我不厌其烦地叨扰您
Allow me to weary you with some details of my day?
你? 叨扰我? 探长
You? Weary me, Inspector?
你曾经送走的那个女孩
That girl you once ran.
那是Lucy 她是个好姑娘
Lucy. A good girl.
她离开我们这里 有了更好的归宿
She left for what we hoped were better times.
不管是不是真是更好的归宿
Better or no,
今天早晨她出现在我的警局 衣服上血迹斑斑
she appears this morning at my station, striped in blood,
为她死去的母亲恸哭
keening after her dead mother.
我听说这事儿了 也为她诚挚地哀悼
I've heard of it. And I mourn for her.
恩  的确
Hmm. Yes.
那个叫Roach的男人也一样
And the man, too, Roach.
他的颈动脉被一个锋利的折叠刀切开
His carotid opened with a stab of a honed switch-blade.
我希望您不是在含沙射影些什么吧 Reid先生
I prefer you spare me that imagery, Mr Reid.
您已经敏感地联想到了什么 不是吗
Your sensitivities affronted, are they?
Jackson上校桌子上的这种植物
This plant on Captain Jackson's desk.
它怎么了
What of it?
薄荷 是不是
Pennyroyal, is it not?
我对那个男人放在房间里的东西可不感兴趣
What that man keeps in this room, I find I prefer not to inquire.
那让我来启发你吧
Then perhaps I might educate you?
这是我的荣幸
I'd be honoured.
薄荷叶 一旦被浸泡酿造
Pennyroyal, when brewed strong as an infusion,
就可能会导致流产
may bring on miscarriage.
真令人感到惊讶
I confess I am surprised a
一个做这种行当的女人竟然会不懂这个
woman in your line of work, ignorant of this.
我能说什么呢 Reid先生
What can I say, Mr Reid?
我们这的姑娘们都小心谨慎
We are cautious in this house.
我要说的是 Eames小姐
Miss Eames is, I would say,
已经有近三个月的身孕了
a little under three month pregnant.
那我再次为她表示诚挚的哀悼
Then I mourn for her once more.
正如我所说的 小心谨慎
As I say - cautious.
你最好快去看看医生 Susan
You best attend to that, Susan.
枪伤很容易引起败血症的
A bullet wound might soon go septic.
想一想我会交待出谁的名字吧
Think of the names I can speak of!
想象你们有多少人来我这儿消遣过
The many men of yours whose pleasure's been found in my house!
他们比你的地位高多了
Those ranked higher than you...!
你们能快点弄走她吗
Will you get her locked down!
你  还有你 你们都曾是我的常客 座上宾
You! And you! And you have all been guests in my house!
跟我来 Jackson
With me, Jackson.
不 Reid
No, Reid!
我发誓 我对她的所作所为真的毫无头绪
I swear it, I have no clue as to what she's doing here.
装得真像啊 上校
How skilled you are, Captain.
你竟然能口口声声的说出
Your claims to know nothing
你对你自己屋檐下发生的事一无所知
of what takes place beneath your own roof.
我对我自己感到无比失望
I am dismayed at myself,
我竟然会相信一个如此破绽百出的人
that I would trust a man so transparently false.
你们两个 - 你和Susan
The two of you - you and Susan
由你们两个精心编造的谎言
the lies that you hide behind,
我眼睁睁地看着而没有验证的谎言
lies that I have allowed to go untested.
仅仅凭着自己愚蠢的直觉
Allowed in the foolish
期许着这其中可能会有误会
instinct that some good might come from it!
你还值得我对你的信任吗
That you might be worth the faith that I have placed in you!
我值得的 Reid
I am, Reid.
你现在是在盛怒之下
You are in a rage
我也理解你的愤怒 但是我...
and I understand that rage, but I...
不
No.
你明知道她的罪责
You knew of her guilt and
只有偷偷摸摸的人才会这样保守秘密
a man who holds secrets is a secretive man.
可是你也有权发表意见 不是么
And you have the right to pronounce on that, do you?
关于你所肩负的这个烂担子
That mess about your shoulder.
所有目睹了这件事的人 这个警局里的所有人
All who have laid eyes on it, every man in this station
对于这件事都三缄其口 即便这发生在他们之间
too afraid to talk about it even amongst themselves.
在那之后Drake有调查过吗
Does Drake enquire after it?
我敢打包票他是不会调查的
Because I'd lay money on it that he doesn't.
知道么 Reid 那是因为他对你忠心耿耿
Well, that's loyalty for you, Reid.
狗是不能质疑主人的辛勤和动机的
A dog unable to question the pain or motivation of the man
于是只好不安地把尾巴摇来摆去
that it tails about the place.
还有 我想说问你的是
Well, I shall ask you.
我想知道你女儿到底出了什么...
I'd hear you speak of what befell your girl...
你又提她了 我压根不想在你做了那档子事后
You ever speak of her again, I shall not trouble myself with
再被你质问起这件破事儿 上校
asking after the secrets of your life, Captain.
我可以把你锁进地底下的单人监狱
I shall chain you in a cell underground
然后用警棍狠狠抽你直到你知无不言言无不尽
and take billy club to you until they pour from you like water.
我说的够清楚了吗
Am I clear?
你要这样对我吗
Am I?
这样对待毫无过错的我
My innocence in all this?
那儿还有个身中枪伤的嫌犯
There is a suspect down the way with a bullet wound,
需要消毒和缝补伤口
requiring disinfection and needlework.
你都没有试图遮掩过你的罪行么
'You make no attempt to hide your guilt.'
为什么要那么做  我不觉得那有什么见不得光的
Why should I? I feel no shame for the act.
那个畜生杀死了那女人
The animal had killed the woman,
并且还想对Lucy做同样的事
was set to do the same to Lucy.
换做你你也会做出跟我一样的选择 探长
I did only as you would have done, Inspector.
你觉得我会相信你么
I should take your word for that?
随你的便 探长  这就是真相
Take what you will, Inspector. It is the truth.
轻点儿 你这庸医
Careful, Quack!
真相么 就你们两个吗
The truth, and the two of you?
再要找出第三个同伙可不容易
Three unlikelier bedfellows a man would struggle to find.
没错
Indeed.
想问什么就问吧 Reid先生
You ask your questions, Mr Reid.
我将会一一作答
I will answer and then
然后由你来判定我是否如实回答了
you may decide if I do so truthfully or no.
谁带你去的狗脖儿胡同
What brought you to Dog's Neck?
- Lucy   - 她邀请你去的么
- Lucy. - She invited you?
- 是我偷偷跟过去的  - 从哪儿开始跟的
- I followed her there. - From?
忐忑街
Tenter Street.
两年来她音讯全无
Two years and not a word,
我甚至不清楚她是否还活着
not a solitary clue as to whether she lived or breathed.
直到有一天 她突然跑到我这儿 穿着不菲
Then, dressed fine as a lady, she knocks on my door.
她来做什么
What did she want?
她想重操旧业
Her old room back.
但你不是说她穿得很好吗
But she was dressed fine, you say?
我也不知道缘由 警长 可那就是事实
I have no explanation for it, Sergeant, just the fact of it.
然后你怎么跟她说的 Susan
Then what did you say to her, Susan?
听着 无论是否接受过良好教育
That, thoroughbred or no,
一个怀着三个月身孕的人都不可能跑这儿来接客
three months pregnant, she was no use whatsoever to your stable.
然后呢
Then what?
为什么问我
Why ask me?
你这么喜欢她 当时想必很懊悔吧
I imagine, being fond of her, you felt remorse.
于是你匆忙追赶她 还没来得及放下手中的薄荷
And you hurried after the girl, Pennyroyal in hand,
想告诉她 一旦她卸下了心理负担
to tell her that, were she to find herself free of her burden,
你这里仍会对她敞开门扉
she might once again be welcome.
对么
Hmm?
我所感兴趣的是你在那之后的见闻
But it is what you found there that interests me the most.
我听到她的声音从街道那头传来
I heard her from the street.
- 她对他大发脾气   - 对Margaret吗
- She raged at him. - Margaret?
是因为什么
On what topic?
他们扭打在一起
They were flattening the place.
他是来收房租的
He wanted his dues before they did so.
不是的
No.
她尖声指控着他的所作所为
She screamed of what she knew of him.
说她再也不会保持静默了
And that she would be silent no longer.
而他威胁她说
And he said that she would if
要是再不闭嘴的话 就杀了她
she knew what would allow her to keep on breathing.
我听到了玻璃碎裂的声音
I heard glass break.
玻璃瓶砸向他脑袋的声音吗
The bottle against his head?
还有手枪的响声
The reports of a revolver.
- Lucy的尖叫声   - 然后你进去了
- Lucy screaming. - You entered.
Lucy当时已经歇斯底里了
Lucy was hysteric.
于是你拔出刀
You produced your blade.
从背后...
You cut...
捅进他的脖子
from behind.
之后Lucy怎么样了
And what of Lucy?
我把她留在那儿
I left her there.
在秽土和污血中蠕动着
Squirming in the dirt.
你瞪着我干嘛
Why d'you stare?
这已经结案了   - Reid
It is a case solved. - Reid.
等会儿 美国佬 快走开
No longer, American, away with ya.
Reid 你真的打算因此处她的罪吗
Reid, do you intend to charge her on this?
就因为救了一个女孩的性命?
For saving a girl's life?
但她也亲手杀了人
A man was killed by her hand.
一个死有余辜的混账畜生
A slumlord ape set on murder.
那也是杀人
Still a man.
可你怎么不想想看为什么这个人
And you never thought it worth asking why this man took
要把手枪对准一个弱女子
a pistol to this woman.
他是感受到了什么样的威胁?
Or whose threat he carried with him?
Jackson上校 我想
Captain Jackson, I shall be
我完全有权利处理自己得到的调查结果
the master of all enquiries I make of myself.
请把门关上 警长
Door, please, Sergeant.
你觉得有必要想这个问题么 长官
Is it worth asking? Do you think, sir?
是的 Bennet  我想有必要
Yes, Bennet. I suspect it is.
David 安静些  乖乖躺下睡觉 晚安
David, be quiet. Down and sleep. Goodnight.
- 晚安 阿姨   - 晚安 晚安 快睡吧
- Goodnight, Miss. - Good night, good night. Sleep!
晚安安 做个好梦
'Go'natt. Sov Gott.
哦 Ellie 我找到你的洋娃娃了
Oh, Ellie, I have your dolly.
拿好了... 快躺好  晚安
There... tuck down. Good night.
快睡吧 晚安
Go to sleep. Good night.
哦 不
Oh, no!
Betsy Betsy
Betsy, Betsy.
Betsy  Betsy
Betsy? Betsy?
Goren小姐
Miss Goren?
似乎我总是给你带来暴力和苦痛
It seems all I bring to you is violence and distress.
快找到孩子们吧 求您了 探长
Find the children, please, Inspector.
Lucy Eames
Lucy Eames.
你说她在两年前就
Two years since, you say she
毫无征兆地从你那儿离开了
walked away from your house with no warning?
我是这么说过
I do.
我想那样的话很接近
The oldest child found in that room,
案发现场年龄大一些的孩子出生的时候
I guess she approached that age.
- 你赞同么   - 是的
- Do you agree? - Mmm.
那么让我来告诉你我的猜想
Then I suggest this to you.
当年你把她赶出来
That you cast her out for the
是出于和你那天把她赶出来同样的原因
same reason you cast her out this day just passed,
那就是她怀孕了 没有办法再接客
that she was pregnant and no longer welcome in your house.
你觉得我铁石心肠是么 探长
You think me callous, Inspector.
或许我的确如此
And perhaps I am that.
但是对于那个女孩子 我像爱妹妹般爱她
But I loved that girl like a sister.
她从未说过她当初为何要离开
And she never did say what took her away.
但我有我的原则
But I had my theories.
接着说
Proceed.
她最初的...发作...
The first of her... attacks...
你是说她的痉挛吗
The fits from which she suffers?
那是她离开前两个月的事了
It had come two months previous.
几乎把那个Thomas吓个半死
Near scared the Thomas with whom
就是点她的那个客人
she was engaged, to his death.
之后她还有再发作过么
There were more?
大概还有过五次吧 而且一次比一次严重
Perhaps five, graver too.
我们发现她在最后一个客人也离开她后就走了
We found her gone the day after the last one had left her.
我想 她或许是去接受治疗了吧
My belief? She went to find their remedy.
先生们 请走这边
Gentlemen, please, come this way.
在你们与她接触的治疗期间
In the treatment you conducted with her,
她有没有谈及过她以前生的孩子
did she speak at all of children born unto her?
没有
She did not.
也没提过她现在怀着的这个吗
Nor of the child she carries in her belly now?
Reid先生 我的病人们
Mr Reid, my patients
无论是以前的 现在的 还是将来的...
past, present, future...
我没有自己的家庭 所以
I have no family of my own and as a consequence,
他们对我来说显得倍加重要
they are doubly precious to me.
这种感情让我无法轻视他们或是打探他们的隐私
Such love means I will not judge them nor demand their secrets.
他们来到这里 张开双臂请求帮助
They come to me, arms wide for assistance
那么我就会无差别地提供援助
and I render it without condition.
除非Lucy她主动来到我面前
Until Lucy chooses freely to tell me
向我倾诉她过往生活的一切
the details of her life away from here,
我是不会向她询问那些的
I will not ask her of them.
但同样的 我也希望你能谅解我 医生
Then that - and I hope you will forgive me for this, doctor -
这是我的职责
that must be my task.
Lucy
Lucy.
我替Susan女士问候你
I bring greetings from Miss Susan.
Susan女士是位淑女
Miss Susan is a lady.
你也是的 Lucy
As are you, Lucy.
我不是 先生 我曾经可以是
Not I, sir. I would be so.
但我现在不是
But am not.
是谁这么说的
And who is it says so?
是这个现世 它的法则
The world. Its law.
上天的法则
God's law.
仅仅因为你未婚先孕?
Because you have children and are unmarried?
有很多原因 先生
Many reasons, sir.
告诉我 Lucy 为什么
Tell me, Lucy, what,
你昨天为什么要到Susan女士那儿去
what was it brought you to Miss Susan yesterday?
她把我送走了
Miss Susan sent me away.
我知道 我知道的
I know, I know.
但是 在两年后你怀上了孩子
But, after two years and with child inside you.
这令你陷入绝望
It is desperate of you.
告诉我 Lucy 请告诉我那个带给你绝望的人的名字
Tell me, Lucy, please, will you name that despair?
Lucy Lucy
Lucy? Lucy?
你母亲照顾的那些孩子
The children that your mother cared for,
还有你怀着的这个孩子
the child that is inside you now.
谁是他们的父亲 Lucy
Which man is father to them, Lucy?
是同一个人 对么
It is but one man, is it not?
别害怕 孩子
Do not be frighted, child.
我会保护好你的周全
It is in my gift to guarantee your safety.
不 我办不到
No, no I cannot!
不 我办不到 办不到
No, I cannot, I cannot, no!
镇定 镇定下来 孩子
Calm. Calm. Calm, child!
好了 都过去了
There... all right.
Eames小姐的治疗药剂
Miss Eames' medication.
Reid先生想要知道它的成分
Mr Reid would know its contents.
Hobbs Hobbs Hobbs 慢下来
Hobbs, Hobbs, Hobbs, slow down,
再说一遍 再来一遍   - 是的 长官
say again, say again. - Yes sir.
长官 Gordon Roach 就是那个被杀的收租人
Sir, Gordon Roach - that's the murdered rent collector, sir
拥有一家名为Roach Collections的公司
has a company name of Roach Collections.
挺会玩儿的
Imaginative.
是的...诶 不对
Yes... No.
Roach Collections公司存入款项
Roach Collections pays into
然后收到来自信托的定期津贴
and receives stipend from a trust.
信托叫什么名
Name of?
Stickleton  Stickleton信托
Stickleton. The Stickleton Trust.
有它的入注会员么
Its board members?
没有登记 只知道一个律师的名字
Not listed. The only name that of a lawyer.
是个姓Pinch的先生
A Mr Pinch.
我已经拜访过Pinch先生
Now, I visited Mr Pinch
好吧其实是Pinch先生的员工
well, Mr Pinch's clerk, that is.
并且让他知道这个案子的重要性...
And impressed on him the value of this...
好了 好了 Hobbs 快跳过这些
Yes, yes, Hobbs, skip to it.
长官 Stickleton信托唯一的受托人
Sir, the only trustee of the Stickleton Trust
就是Stanley Bone先生
is Mr Stanley Bone.
Drake警长 快跟我来
Sergeant Drake! With me!
Stanley Bone 把你知道的关于他的全部说出来
Stanley Bone. Everything you have.
立刻
Now.
弄错了
Hang it.
Fred Best跟你说过吧 他需要些东西作为报酬
Fred Best tells you he needs something shown in return.
你照我问的回答 我会给你些情报的
You do as I ask, I will
但倘若你跟他们串通一气
give to you a story that, though you connive
天堂有路你不走 地狱无门你非来
and bribe your way to the
就休怪我给你好看了
devil himself - it will not be bettered.
继续说   - 比如Stanley Bone
Go on. - How Stanley Bone
那个秘密房东 是怎么
secret slumlord -
被一个老鸨的行为揭发出真面目的
is exposed by the actions of a whore-runner.
贪污和性丑闻 Best先生
Corruption and sex, Mr Best.
没有什么比这更甜美诱人的了
Surely it does not come more honeyed than that.
哦 太好了 老天
Oh, yeah, Mama!
我可终于找到你了 Reid在哪
I have you now! Where's Reid?
他出去了 过会儿就回来
He's out, he may be some time.
你最好告诉我他去了哪
Well you're going to tell me.
否则我这就射死Hobbs
Or I'm going to shoot Hobbs here.
放轻松 Hobbs  老兄 我是开玩笑的
Relax, Hobbs. Man, I'm only joking.
就算我开枪杀了我妈 也不会杀了你的
I could no more shoot you than I could shoot my own mother.
Artherton 就另当别论了...
Artherton, on the other hand...
如你所知 探长
As you know, Inspector,
他是新郡议会在一月份任命的第一批议员之一
he was one of the first raised up in January by our new council.
现在三月份他和他的朋友们对
Now in March he and his friends agree that the Dockhead slum
清拆萨瑟克区的坞首贫民窟
in Southwark make way for
以修建S&C铁路和它的第一条隧道的议案表示支持
the S&C Railway and its very first tunnel.
坞首地区属于
The Dockhead was also owned
- Stickleton信托吗   - 是的
- and collected by the Stickleton Trust? - It was.
因此Bone先生实际上是支持了强制收购自己的贫民窟
Thus Mr Bone recommends the compulsory purchase of his own slum.
嗯哼 而且收益颇丰
Mm-hm and profits tidily.
Best先生 我上次见到你时
Mr Best, the last I saw you, you made heavy weather of matters
你对Bone的私人情况发表了长篇大论
that relate more closely to Mr Bone's personal status.
是的 我说的都是事实
I did. It is true.
你可以详细阐述一下吗
Elaborate, if you please?
Bone先生并非生来就野心勃勃
Mr Bone is a man who came to ambition late.
他的童年并不幸福 被痉挛所困扰
His youth was not a happy one. Beset with fits.
他是癫痫患者?
He is epileptic?
曾经是 他最后治好了
Was. He eventually found the cure.
治愈了?  治疗方法从何而来?
And the cure? Where was it found?
你要么让我过去 要么就尝尝子弹的滋味吧
You will let me pass, or you will suck on this iron!
先生 停下  你不能进去
Sir, stop! You can't go in there!
Drake
Drake.
听着 我发誓我不会杀你
Look, I swear I'm not going to shoot you,
只要... 告诉Reid...
only... tell Reid...
那个药瓶...Lucy的药物...额...
that the vial... Lucy's medication... Uh...
什么  那是什么
What? What is it?
那是苯丙胺
It is amphetamine!
苯丙胺 一种中枢兴奋药 可减少疲乏和产生自我欢快的感觉
反复使用会导致病态嗜好 甲基苯丙胺又称冰毒
给Bone先生治疗的医生
The doctor who gave Mr Bone his cure.
- 他叫Crabbe 是不是   - 是的 Reid先生
- His name is Crabbe, is it not? - It is, Mr Reid.
我们走  啊 最后一个问题
We go. Ah, one last question.
你嘲讽过他的单身状态
You jibed about his bachelor status.
你为什么要笑他
What did you mean by this?
这是最后一个关键点 Reid先生
That is the last piece of my puzzle, Mr Reid.
据说他在外面藏了个情妇
There was tell he had a woman cached away somewhere
还有一些私生子
and a set of bastards, too
你找到他们了吗
And did you find them?
没有 Reid先生 这是遗憾之处 嗯?
Never could, Mr Reid. More's the pity, eh?
确实
Indeed.
你的马车到了
Your carriage is here.
这马车将带你去收获这个城市里
A carriage that takes you to honour the
又一段值得庆祝的荣耀
latest chapter of your ever more celebrated life in this city.
想一想
Think on that.
还记得你第一次来见我是怎样的吗
Remember how you lived the first you came to me -
被痉挛所折磨 依赖着你残忍的妻子苟活着
cursed by fits and reliance on your merciless wife.
你觉得我忘却了吗
Do you think I forget?
难道我没有对你为我做的一切感怀于心吗
Am I not grateful for what you have done for me?
我怀疑你是否对我们面前存在的阻碍有所行动
I question your commitment to all that still lies ahead of us.
Roach杀了那个女人
Roach silenced the woman.
我与孩子们分离
I have had the children separated
不远百里来到这儿 听从了你的建议
and removed a hundred mile from here, as you suggested.
我指的并不是你那些不受宠爱的私生子们
I do not refer to your unloved bastards,
这你知道
as you well know.
能成功建起这个疗养院 你功不可没
It was your success had this sanatorium built,
而她就是我对你的回礼
and she my gift to you in return.
一个孩子 逐渐盛开为成熟女人 她所目见的
A child, blooming into woman, who would see in you
并不是年轻时口吃而癫狂的你
not the stammering lunatic of your youth,
而是一个充满希望和力量的你
but a vision of strength and hope.
你已经享受过她给你带来的满足
You have enjoyed her.
可她现在已经没有用处了
But she is all used now.
而且必须把她对你所有的记忆通通抹去
And must have her mind cleaned of all she knows of you.
但她还如此年轻...
But she is so young...
也许她也能和我一样在你引领下找寻到救赎
She too may find the temperance you have led me toward.
不 她的成长历程比你更糟糕
No. She grows ever more disturbed.
而且那个Reid已经让一切失去了可能
And this Reid draws close.
我绝对不会允许你
I will not allow you to
毁了我为你筑造出的人生
make ruins of the life I have built for you.
她必须就此沉默 快点忘记她吧
She must be silenced so put her from your mind,
就像忘记你记忆中曾经的自己
as you have the memory of the man you once were.
然后让我赐予她永恒的安宁
And leave me to bring her a more permanent peace.
Karl 我会去和她告别的
Karl, I would say goodbye.
谢谢你 护士
Thank you, nurse.
Stanley
Stanley?
只说你应该说的
Say what you need to say.
再见 Lucy 再见 我的爱
Goodbye, Lucy, goodbye, my love.
Stanley  Stanley 他们要把我带到哪儿去
Stanley? Stanley, where do they take me?
我...我又有宝宝了 Stanley
I... I've got another inside me, Stanley,
又有个宝宝了 Stanley?
I got another. Stanley?
没事的 Bone议员
It's all right, Councillor Bone.
只有拆除一两个贫民窟才能建成铁路
We cannot build a railway without that we demolish a slum or two.
Sta...
等等  那是Bone
Wait. That was Bone!
暂且不管  我走我们的
It can wait. We keep our course.
安静 Lucy  嘘 想象一下
Hush, Lucy. Shh, imagine it.
一切平静至极  没有疑虑 没有烦扰
A calm entire. Hmm, no questions, no hurtful thoughts.
没有紧迫和不快的欲望
No urgent and unhappy desires.
归于平静
Simply peace.
你找到我们了
You found us.
这可不容易  你把避难所藏得太好了
It was not easy. You've hidden this refuge well.
但对你保护下的人们来说是件好事
But that is a benefit to those you house.
- 是呢   - Goren女士
- It is. - Miss Goren?
探长
Inspector.
Nicholas? Betsy?  你们好
Nicholas? Betsy? Hello!
过来 给我抱抱
Come here, you!
来吧 我们进去 好吗
Come on, let's go inside, shall we?
来给你看看Reid太太帮我们找的屋子
And show you the room Mrs Reid has got for us.
好不好 来吧
Yeah? Come on.
你喝茶吗 Goren女士
Will you take tea, Miss Goren.
好的 谢谢
Yes, thank you.
先生们 女士们  开关已经打开
Gentlemen! Ladies! The switch is thrown.
这条线路正式开通了
The line is live.
在这片土地之下 电子时代莅临了
And beneath this earth here, the electric age forges on.
这条铁路 这条地下
This railway, this underground
铁路是一切的奠基石 而我们
railway is the capstone of all that we -
作为幸运的人民公仆
your grateful servants
还将在这片土地上继续有所作为
would build here.
女士们 先生们 这将是一个崭新的城市的根基
The foundation, ladies and gentlemen, of a new city.
尽管崛起于腐臭的污泥
A city that - though it rises from dank and fetid earth -
这个城市会如同明媚的夏日清晨般熠熠生辉
will gleam with the purpose and clarity of a summer morning.
如果说未来意味着什么 那它便意味着希望
Because if the future stands for anything - it stands for hope!
你没必要做这些
You do not have to do this thing.
有必要 探长
I do, Inspector.
H警区的Reid探长 您来这有何贵干
H Division's Inspector Reid! What intrusion is this?
是的 Stanley 我仍旧拥有理智
Yes, Stanley. I still have my wits.
女士 女士  你叫什么名字
Miss, Miss. What is your name?
她的名字并不重要  重要的是她的故事
Her name is not relevant. Her story is.
我对你知根知底 Stanley Bone
I know you, Stanley Bone.
你向这些好人宣告
You proclaim to these
言辞中充满对未来的光明的希望
good people about the future's gleaming hope,
但说出这些话语的你却是虚伪的
but the tongue you speak with is forked.
以及你所描绘的未来
And the future you speak of,
实则建立于邪恶与腐败之上
it is built on evil and corruption.
你把我当做你的奴隶
You had me as your slave,
拒绝我们的孩子...
denied our children...
放任我母亲被杀害
had my mother murdered
你还把我送到一个活生生的地狱
and you would have
倘若不是有这位探长的存在
sent me to a living hell
我恐怕至今也无法走出
had it not been for this inspector here.
你简直不是人 你就是一个
You are no man, but you are a beast that has risen
从你所深挖的地下世界中长大的牲畜
deep from the earth in which you dig into.
Stanley Bone先生
Mr Stanley Bone!
你去阻止警察
You halt for the police!
你们小心 远离轨道  谁快点去关了它
Watch yourself, off the track. Turn it off, somebody!
我的天哪
Christ alive!
你出名了
You're famous. From a
从莱曼街的监狱到今天的头版头条
Leman Street cell to the front page in a day.
一定会有人为你着迷
Someone must be fond of you.
哼 这种名誉是暂时的
Hmm, such fame is impermanent.
最好如此  否则
You'd better hope so. Otherwise,
无法继续生存下去的就会是你我二人
it's going to be you and me lacking in permanence.
我们需要对付的一定不是普通的盗贼
Whoever we contend with here, they are no ordinary cracksmen.
再来
Again!
法律面前人人平等 他们不是吗
All men stand equal before the law, do they not?
这就是法律
That is the law.
这是你的法律 是你的吗
It is your law. Is it yours?